Pushkar Patil

Cloud Engineer

38, Maheshnagar, Pimpri, Pune, Maharashtra, India - 411018 | +91 7058399950 | pushkar.patil@sapphireinfotech.co.in

Profile

Experienced Cloud Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Python (Programming Language), Terraform, Microsoft Azure, Linux, and Amazon Web Services (AWS). Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Engineering focused in Computer Science from All India Shivaji Memorial Societys College of Engineering, Pune.

Certifications

Amazon Web Services Solutions Architect - Associate (Credential ID: 644CTSVKHB41QL9Y)

Amazon Web Services Developer - Associate (Credential ID: 860LS3L1N1E41QSP)

Amazon Web Services Solutions Architect - Professional (Credential ID: 8PLN6B6C3EVEQFWM)

Amazon Web Services Machine Learning - Specialty (Credential ID: 1CQ5RJWL1E11QMCJ)

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (Credential ID: 990349125)

Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate (AZ-104) (Credential ID: H551-2691)

Aviatrix Certified Engineer - Multi-Cloud Network Professional (Credential ID 2020-8636)

Employment History

Freelancer July 2019 - Jan 2020

Clients: holytripz.com & neervana.in - Pune, India

- Manage Web Services and web application with CloudWatch monitoring tool
- Apache with PHP EC2 instances with Load Balancing in VPC in public Subnet
- RDS instances as back end supporting EC2 instances apache web-server application
- EFS (NFS service on AWS), Apache Web Services, Firewall and Security Groups.
- SSL on Load Balancer with Auto Scaling
- · Setup/Managing VPC, Subnets; make connection between different zones; Blocking suspicious IP/subnet via ACL.
- Create/Managing buckets on S3 (CLI) and store DB and logs backup, upload multimedia files for CDN service.
- Creating/Managing DNS records on Amazon Route 53.
- Creating/Managing AMI/Snapshots/Volumes, Upgrade/downgrade AWS resources (CPU, Memory, EBS)

Senior Cloud Engineer Jan 2020 - Dec 2021

Sapphire Infotech Pvt Ltd - Mumbai, India

- Experienced in SAP on AWS Cloud Advisory / Assessment Services
- Experienced in SAP Disaster Recovery & Business Continuity Solution on AWS Cloud
- Experienced in SAP Lift & Shift & OS/DB Migrations on AWS Cloud
- Experienced in SAP Business Suite on HANA Migrations on AWS Cloud
- Experienced in Automated SAP Migrations using CloudEndure Migration Tools
- Automated SAP HANA Backup using AWS Backint Agent
- Auto Scaled SAP Application Instances Using AWS
- Actively Participated in AWS SAP Competency Program
- Actively Participated in AWS EC2 Service Delivery Program

Education

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science

August 2015 - May 2019

AISSMS COE, Pune - Pune

Final Year Project:

- · Created a system which can act as portable storage device as well as also serve the purpose of virtual personal assistant.
- Published IRJET research paper titled "Voice Controlled Personal Assistant Bot with Smart Storage" (e-ISSN: 2395-0056, p-ISSN: 2395-0072).